You have got to try this cheesecake.
你得試試這塊起司蛋糕
You know, I'm not that much of a sweet tooth..
我不是那麼喜歡吃甜食…
Oh, my God, it's so creamy!
我的天啊，它好香濃
That's the best cheesecake I've ever had!
那是我吃過最棒的起司蛋糕！
Where did you get this?
你在哪裡買到它？
It was at the front door when I got home. Somebody sent it to us.
我回家時它就已經放在門口了 有人把它寄給我們
This isn't addressed to you.
收件人不是你
This is addressed to Mrs. Braverman downstairs!
收件人是樓下的佈雷曼太太！
Thief!
小偷！
I didn't read the box before I opened it...
我沒看收件人姓名就打開了盒子…
and you can't return a box after you opened it!
盒子已經打開了就無法退還！
-Why not? -Because it's too delicious!
-為什麼？ -因為它太好吃了
You stole this cheesecake. That's wrong.
你偷了這個起司蛋糕，那是不對的
No, it'll be okay because Mrs. Braverman will send for a free one.
不，沒關係的，因為佈雷曼太太 會免費再收到一個
That way, we all win.
那可是雙贏的局面
The only losers are the big cheesecake conglomerate...
唯一的輸家是大型起司蛋糕店…
"Mama's Little Bakery."
「小媽媽的麵包店」
I feel terrible.
我覺得好難過
I'm a horrible, horrible person.
我是個大壞蛋
I'm sorry, what?
對不起，你說什麼？
The One With All The Cheesecakes
本集播出：起司蛋糕
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
I should get going. Big day at work.
我得走了，我今天工作很忙
You know how I'm in a coma?
你們知道我怎麼會昏迷不醒嗎？
Today they do a test on me and it turns out I'm not brain-dead.
今天他們要幫我做檢查 結果發現我沒有腦死
So..
所以…
Mr. Smarty Pants.
聰明先生
It's just my character that's not brain-dead.
沒有腦死的是我演的角色
Phoebe, still on for tonight?
菲比，今晚的事沒取消吧？
-Absolutely. -I'll see you at 8.
-當然 -八點見
What's at 8?
什麼東西八點見？
Dinner. We get together about once a month to discuss the rest of you.
我們約好吃晚餐，我們大約 一個月會約一次去討論你們的事
Wow! Did not know that.
哇！我真的不知道
May I say how lovely you look today?
我能說你今天看起來很漂亮嗎？
Duly noted.
那當然
zSo for tomorrow, do you want to rent a car and drive down together?
明天你要租輛車一起開過去嗎？
-What are you talking about? -Cousin Frannie's wedding.
-你在說什麼？ -芬妮表妹的婚禮
You were invited?
你被邀請了？
No.
不
Oh, my God, I can't believe this.
我的天啊，我不敢相信
I thought only Mom and Dad were invited.
我以為他們只邀請了爸跟媽
From the ages of 7 to 9,  Frannie and I were inseparable.
七歲到九歲，芬妮跟我形影不離
Maybe since the age of 9,  Frannie's made some new friends.
或許九歲後，芬妮交了新朋友
It's probably just a mistake. Let me call Aunt Cheryl.
或許這只是個誤會 我打電話去問雪若阿姨
Maybe you are invited and the invitation got lost in the mail.
或許他們邀請你了，只是請帖寄丟了
You call her and tell her that when we were kids...
你可以打電話告訴她，我們小時候…
her precious Frannie tried to undress me several times.
她的寶貝芬妮好幾次想脫光我的衣服
If I hadn't stopped her, there wouldn't be a wedding to go to.
要不是我阻止了她，她也結不了婚
She tried to undress me too.
她也想脫我的衣服
I used to undress my cousin Glenn.
我以前會幫葛蘭表弟脫衣服
Joseph Francis Tribbiani, are you home yet?
喬瑟夫法蘭西斯崔比亞尼 你回家了嗎？
I think he's still out. What's wrong?
我想他還沒有回家，怎麼了？
I'll tell you, Rachel Karen Greene.
我得告訴你，瑞秋凱倫葛林
I had plans with Joey, and he left me this note.
我跟喬伊有約，他留了這張字條給我
"Phoebe, can't make it. Got a date. Talk to you later.
菲比，我沒辦法赴約 我有約會，待會再談
"Big Daddy."
大爹地
-"Big Daddy"? -That's a nickname we were trying.
-「大爹地」？ -那是我們之間的暱稱
You know what nickname never caught on? "The Ross-a-tron."
你知道什麼樣的暱稱，不會跟 別人重覆嗎？「羅斯原子超人」
Here's Joseph Francis!
喬瑟夫法蘭西斯回來了！
Wait, what are you middle-naming me for?
等一下，你幹嘛叫我的全名？
I left you a note.
我留了字條給你
That doesn't give you the right to ditch me!
那不是你放我鴿子的好理由
You can cancel plans with friends if there's a possibility for sex.
如果你有機會上床 當然可以取消跟朋友的約會
He's right. That is the rule.
他說的對，這是規則
I don't accept it. When we make plans, I expect you to show up.
我無法接受這種事 我們約好後，我期待你會出現
I'm not a way to kill time till you meet someone better.
我不是你泡到馬子前 打發時間的代替品
Boyfriends and girlfriends will come and go, but this is for life.
男女朋友來來去去 但朋友是一輩子的
I'm so sorry. I had no idea it would bother you this much.
我真的很抱歉，我不知道 這對你來說那麼重要
Well, it does.
喔，它的確很重要
Well, can I make it up to you?
我可以彌補你嗎？
I'm sorry.
對不起
How about dinner tomorrow night? I'll pay for myself.
明天晚上一起吃飯吧？我會自己付錢
Okay, you wore me down.
好吧，你說服了我
While you're over there, how about a beer for "The Ross-a-tron"?
既然你站在那邊，拿罐啤酒給 「羅斯原子超人」吧？
"Ross.." Is that back?
「羅斯…」，它又回來了？
The other cheesecake came.
又有起司蛋糕
They delivered it here again.
他們又把它送到這裡來
Just bring it downstairs. What's the problem?
把它送到樓下去，那有什麼問題？
I can't seem to say goodbye.
我不知道該怎麼說再見
Are you serious?
你是說真的嗎？
We ate an entire cake two days ago and you want more?
兩天前我們吃掉 一個蛋糕，你還想再吃？
Well, I've forgotten what it tastes like.
喔，我已經忘記它的味道了
It was cheesecake. It was fine.
它是起司蛋糕，它很好吃
It had a buttery, crumbly, graham cracker crust...
它有又香又濃，酥酥的餅乾…
with a very rich...
還有非常濃郁…
yet light cream cheese filling.
但不油膩的奶油起司
Wow, my whole mouth just filled with saliva.
我的嘴巴全是口水
Know what? Forget it. We're just hungry.
你知道嗎？忘了它，我們只是餓了
We haven't had lunch. We're just lightheaded.
我們沒有吃午餐，所以頭昏腦脹
So let's go have lunch and forget about the cheesecake.
我們去吃午餐，忘了那個起司蛋糕吧
We'll drop it off so we're not tempted.
我們得把它還回去，才不會被誘惑
-Where do you want to eat? -Mama's Little Bakery, Chicago.
-你要去哪裡吃午餐？ -芝加哥小媽媽麵包店
Mei Torme died.
梅爾多米死了
Joey, that paper's like a year old.
喬伊，那是一年前的報紙
Does that mean the Sam Goody's sale is over?
那表示山姆古迪商店 的大特賣結束了？
So, I finally heard back from Aunt Cheryl...
我終於收到雪若阿姨的回音…
and apparently it wasn't a mistake.
很明顯地這不是誤會
There's limited seating..
婚禮現場座位有限…
Limited seating? I am just one tiny person!
座位有限？我是個瘦皮猴！
Yeah, but she doesn't know that.
對，但是她不知道
I mean, the last time she saw you...
我是說上次她看到你…
you'd have turned one of those little wedding chairs into kindling.
你會把婚禮用的小椅子給壓垮
"Limited seating." That's such a lame excuse.
「座位有限」那真是個爛借口
That's not the reason she's not inviting me.
那不是她不邀請我的原因
What's the big deal? I wasn't invited to the ceremony, just the reception.
那有什麼大不了的呢？ 我沒辦法觀禮，只能去吃喜酒
If it makes you feel any better, Joan and I will just make an appearance...
如果這能讓你覺得開心一點 瓊安跟我只會去亮個相…
and then we'll leave early as a sign of protest.
我們會提早離開，以示抗議
-Joan? -Yeah, my date.
-瓊安？ -對，她是我的女伴
Assistant professor in linguistics. Tall, very beautiful.
她是語言學系的助教，又高又漂亮
And despite what some people say,  not broad-backed.
雖然有些人說，別挑太魁梧的女孩
Wait a minute. You got "Ross Geller and Guest"?
等一下，你收到的喜帖 是「請攜伴參加」？
I wasn't invited,  and you got "and Guest"?
我沒有被邀請 你卻可以「攜伴參加」？
Excuse me, I do have to interrupt on Ross' behalf.
對不起，我真的得解釋羅斯的行為
I think the rule applies here.
我想規則也適用在這裡
Since he has a chance to get on broad-back..
因為他有機會跟魁梧女人上床…
Not broad-back!
她沒有那麼魁梧！
Wait a minute. You're bringing me.
等一下，你得帶我去
I can't cancel on Joan.
我不能放瓊安鴿子
-Why not? -Did you not hear me?
-為什麼？ -你沒有聽到嗎？
She's an assistant professor in the linguistics department.
她是語言學系的助教
They're wild.
她們很辣
-Why do you want to come anyway? -Because...
-你到底為什麼想去？ -因為…
she's my cousin.
她是我表妹
I mean, we grew up together.
我們是一起長大的
Family, you know? And all that's important to me.
我們是家人，你知道嗎？ 對我來說那很重要
Okay, all right. I'll take you.
好吧，我帶你去
I'll go call Joan.
我去打電話給瓊安
Oh, that's nice.
那真的是太棒了
Family should be there.
家人應該要出席的
It's her wedding. Happiest day of her life.
這是她的婚禮 她一生中最快樂的日子
We'll see.
我們等著瞧吧
Well, thank you for lunch.
謝謝你請我吃午餐
Wait, I thought you paid.
等一下，我以為你付了錢
Apparently, we don't pay for food anymore.
很明顯的，我們不必再掏錢買食物了
-Do you see what I see? -It's still there.
-我沒有看錯吧？ -它還在那裡
Mrs. Braverman must be out.
佈雷曼太太一定是出去了
She could be out of town. Maybe gone for months.
她可能出城去了 或許幾個月後才會回來
By then, it may spoil. She can't come back to bad cheesecake.
到時候蛋糕一定壞了 不能讓她回來時看到壞掉的起司蛋糕
-It could kill her. -Don't want that.
-她可能會中毒死掉 -我不希望發生那種事
We're protecting her.
我們是在保護她
-We'll take it. -But quick.
-我們把它拿走 -但是快一點
-Why? -I hear her in there.
-為什麼？ -我聽到她在裡面走動的聲音
Go! Go! Go!
快走…
Oh, my God, that's David.
天啊，是大衛
-Who? -David, the scientist guy.
-誰？ -那個科學家大衛
David that I was in love with.
我愛上的那個大衛
Who went to Russia and broke my heart, David.
他到俄國去，傷了我的心，大衛
Oh, my God!
我的天啊！
Say their name enough, they turn around.
只要一直念某人的名字 那個人就會轉過身來
Phoebe.
菲比
David.
大衛
What are you doing? Aren't you supposed to be in Russia?
你在做什麼？你不是在俄國嗎？
I'm just in town for a conference.
我到城裡來開會
God, you look phenomenal.
天啊，你看起來美得出奇
Well...
喔…
Yeah.
對
You look great too. Did you get a haircut?
你看起來也很棒，你剪了頭髮嗎？
Yeah. Well, I got like 30 of them.
對，我大概剪了三十次
Look, I got a confession to make.
聽著，我得跟你坦誠一件事
I was hoping to run into you here.
我希望能在這裡遇到你
I didn't know if I should call. I was only in town a few days...
我不知道該不該打電話給你 我只會在城裡待幾天…
and I didn't want to intrude on your life.
我不想打擾你的生活
I really wanted to see you...
我真的想見你…
but I didn't know if you wanted to see me.
但我不知道你要不要見我
Of course I would want to see you. I think about you all the time.
我當然想見你，我常常想到你
Really? Because I think about you all the time.
真的嗎？因為我也常常想到你
There's a statue in Minsk that reminds me of you so much.
明斯克有一座雕像，讓我常常想起你
It's actually of Lenin...
事實上那是列寧的雕像…
but, you know, at certain angles...
但有些角度…
Anyway, do you want to have dinner tonight?
總之，今晚你想跟我共進晚餐嗎？
Yes.
好
Oh, no!
喔，不！
-What? -I can't.
-什麼？ -我不能
I can't believe I have plans. Can you do it tomorrow?
我不敢相信 我有約了，明天可以嗎？
No, I have to go in a few hours. I have to be on the redeye.
不，再過幾小時我就得離開 我得趕回去
Listen, next time you're in Minsk...
聽著，下次你到明斯克…
Phoebe? Can I talk to you for a second?
菲比，我能跟你談一談嗎？
What are you doing?
你在做什麼？
I have plans with Joey.
我跟喬伊有約
So? He'll understand.
所以呢？他會諒解的
No, he won't. And that's not even the point.
不，他不會的，那根本不是重點
I made a whole speech about how you do not cancel plans with friends.
我教訓他不該見色忘友
And now just because, potentially,  the love of my life...
現在只因為可能是我真愛的人…
returns from Russia for one night...
明天就要回俄國去…
I should change my beliefs?
我就應該改變我的想法？
I should change my beliefs!
我應該改變我的想法！
No. If I don't have my principles,  I don't have anything.
不，如果失去了原則 那麼我什麼都不會有
You're so strong.
你太有說服力了
Or I should rush through dinner with Joey and meet David at 9.
或許我可以趕快跟喬伊吃完晚餐 然後九點跟大衛見面
Oh, my God, that is so good!
我的天啊，那真的是太棒了！
I'm full. And yet I know if I stop eating this...
我吃飽了，但我知道 如果我現在停下來…
I'll regret it.
我會後悔
Hey, what have you got there?
嘿，你們在吃什麼？
Oh, it's...
喔，那是…
It's tofu cake. Want some?
豆腐蛋糕，你要吃一點嗎？
What are you doing tonight?
今晚你要做什麼？
Dude. Dude.
兄弟
Sorry.
對不起
I got plans with Phoebe.
我跟菲比有約
Really? Monica said she had a date at 9.
真的？摩妮卡說她九點有約會
-What? Tonight? -That's what Monica said.
-什麼？今晚？ -摩妮卡是那麼說的
After that speech, she makes a date on the same night she has plans with me?
她教訓了我一頓 卻同時約了我跟她的男伴？
She's trying to pull a fast one on Big Daddy.
她想草草解決大爹地
Here, I think this is us.
好了，我們的位置應該是這一桌
Limited seating, my ass.
座位有限，我的天啊
Let's see who made the cut.
我們來看看誰被邀請了
Hi. I'm Monica Geller.
嗨，我是摩妮卡蓋勒
-How do you know the bride and groom? -I worked with Frannie.
-你們跟新人是什麼關係？ -我是芬妮以前的同事
Used to work with her. Used to.
以前的同事，以前
I'm a relative and I didn't get invited.
我是她的親戚卻沒有被邀請
A blood relative. Blood.
我是她的血親，血
Stop saying "blood" to strangers.
別在陌生人面前提到「血」
And you? How do you know the couple?
你呢？你跟快樂的新人是什麼關係？
We went to college with both of them.
我們是他們的大學同學
Now we live next door.
現在是他們的鄰居
Okay, you're fine.
好吧，你還夠格
-Are you guys ready? -Yes.
-你們要點菜了嗎？ -是的
I'll have a green salad,  house dressing and water's fine.
我要沙拉，特調醬汁，給我水就好了
And for you, sir?
你呢？先生
Yeah. This slow-roasted salmon...
對，慢烤鮭魚…
how slow are we talking?
那到底有多慢呢？
It's already been roasted.
它已經烤好了
Oh, then no. Maybe I should hear the specials again.
那麼我不要，麻煩你 再告訴我一次今日特餐
We've heard the specials three times.
我們已經聽了三次
There's prime rib, mahi-mahi and a very special lobster ravioli.
有烤肋排，鬼頭刀魚 跟特製龍蝦餃子
-Actually, we're out of the ravioli. -Well, that changes everything!
-事實上我們沒有餃子了 -那我們得重來一次
You know what, Phoebe? You were right before.
你知道嗎？菲比 之前你說的話是對的
Friends are so important.
朋友太重要了
Yeah, I'm very wise. I know.
對，我很聰明，我知道
Know what I really want?
你知道我想做什麼嗎？
-What? -Is to have a long, long talk.
-什麼？ -我想花時間跟你長談
You know? Get Joey out on the open road and really open him up.
你知道嗎？告訴我多一點人生道理
-Any progress? -Yes.
-可以點菜了嗎？ -是的
I will have the lobster ravioli.
我要點龍蝦餃子
God, Joey, this is taking forever.
天啊，喬伊，這得花一輩子的時間
-What's the rush? -Well...
-幹嘛這麼急呢？ -喔…
I have an appointment.
我有個約會
And it's very important.
它非常重要
What is it?
怎麼說？
Well...
喔…
it's a date.
我約了一個男人
A date? No, you must be mistaken, because you wouldn't have a date...
你約了男人？不，你一定弄錯了 因為你不能跟男人約會…
on the same night you have plans with a friend.
同時又跟朋友約吃飯
Don't make me feel badly.
別讓我覺得內疚
No, I'm gonna!
不，我就是要那麼做！
You made me feel really guilty about going out with that girl.
我跟那個女孩出去 你讓我覺得非常內疚
Like I did something terrible. Now you're doing the same thing.
好像我做了什麼可怕的事 現在你也那麼做
It's not! It's totally different!
才怪，這完全不一樣！
This is with David. Remember David, the scientist guy?
我跟大衛有約 你還記得科學家大衛嗎？
He's very special to me.
對我來說他非常特別
My girl the other night was special. She was a scientist too.
那晚我約的女孩也很特別 她也是個科學家
-She was? -Well, she graduated high school.
-是嗎？ -她高中畢業
Whatever. Know what?
隨便啦，你知道嗎？
He's only here for four hours and I'm gonna go see him.
他只會在這裡待四小時，我得去見他
-Fine! -Yeah.
-好吧 -對
What are you still doing here? I told you, lobster ravioli!
你還在這裡做什麼？ 我說過了，龍蝦餃子！
I was about to leave. I didn't think you were coming.
我正要離開，我以為你不會來了
I wouldn't have missed this.
我絕不會錯過這次約會
Well, I'm very glad you're here.
我很高興你來了
Oh, you're such a gentleman.
你是個紳士
Come on, we're going to my place.
來吧，到我家去
Are you eating the cheesecake without me?
你想一個人獨吞起司蛋糕？
I will give you $100 to whistle right now.
只要你現在能吹出口哨 我就給你一百塊
-How can you eat it without me? -What'll you do?
-你怎麼可以不管我一個人獨吞？ -你會怎麼做呢？
Tell Monica or Joey? No, you'd have to tell them everything.
告訴摩妮卡或喬伊？ 不，你得把一切都告訴他們
We're dessert stealers. We're living outside the law.
我們是甜點小偷，我們犯了法
I don't trust you with this cake.
我不能讓你跟蛋糕獨處
I got it first,  and I'm taking it back!
我先發現它的，我要把它拿回來！
-What? Oh, no. -Oh, yes.
-什麼？不 -對
You think I trust you with it?
你以為我就能相信你嗎？
No, we'll split it.
不，我們平分它
That's not fair. You had some.
那不公平，你已經吃掉一點了
I think Monica would be very interested to know...
我想摩妮卡一定想知道…
that you called her cheesecake "dry and mealy."
你說她做的起司蛋糕「又乾又粗」
What do we use to split it?
我們要用什麼來切蛋糕？
All right, pick a half.
好了，挑一塊
Well, this side looks bigger.
這塊比較大
But there's more crust on this side.
但這塊餅乾比較多
Maybe if I measure it..
或許我該量一下…
Pick a piece!
快挑一塊
-All right, I pick that one. -It's the smaller piece.
-好吧，我挑那一塊 -那一塊比較小
Okay. There you go.
好了，拿去吧
Enjoy your half, my friend. But that is it.
好好享受你的蛋糕吧 我的朋友，因為大勢已定
No sharing, no switching,  and don't come crying to me...
我不會跟你分，不會跟你換 別哭著跑來找我…
if you eat your piece too fast.
如果你一下子就把蛋糕吃完了
-You gonna give me some of yours? -Oh, no.
-你要給我一點蛋糕嗎？ -不
No switching, no sharing. And don't come crying to me.
我不會跟你分，不會跟你換 別哭著跑來找我
I may just sit here and have my cake all day.
我要坐在這裡 花一整天好好享用我的蛋糕
Just sit here in the hallway and eat my..
我要坐在走廊上吃我的…
Ross, sweetheart!
羅斯，甜心！
Oh, hey, Aunt Millie.
嘿，米莉阿姨
-Isn't it a beautiful wedding? -Yes, it is.
-這個婚禮很溫馨吧？ -沒錯
Every time, on the lips!
她每次都親嘴巴！
Why? Why on the lips?
為什麼？為什麼要親嘴巴？
There's Frannie. Won't she be happy to see me?
芬妮在那邊，她看到我 一定會很高興吧？
You be nice, all right?
你得乖乖的，好嗎？
I didn't bring you to ambush her.
我不是帶你來欺負她
Frannie was the one who showed your Playboys to Mom.
芬妮把你的《花花公子》拿給媽媽看
That bitch.
那個死小孩
Monica!
摩妮卡！
What..?
什麼…？
Am I doing here? Surprised to see me?
我在這裡做什麼？ 你看到我很訝異嗎？
Ross brought me. How do you like that?
羅斯帶我來的，你還喜歡嗎？
Hi, Frannie. Congratulations.
芬妮，恭喜
You invite my whole family, and not me? Why?
你邀請我的家人 卻不邀請我，為什麼？
Why wouldn't you want me here? What could I have done?
你為什麼不希望我來？我做了什麼？
Stuart!
史都華！
I believe you know my husband.
我相信你認識我丈夫
So it's really a question of "who" could you have done.
問題應該是，你把上了「誰」
I hate this, but I have to go.
我討厭這樣，但我得走了
I can't miss my flight.
我不能錯過飛機
I bet there's another flight to Minsk in..
我敢說下一班飛往 明斯克的飛機是在…
July.
七月
That's really beautiful. What does it mean?
那真的好窩心，它是什麼意思？
"Please clean my beakers."
「請幫我把杯子洗乾淨」
I don't get out of the lab much.
我不常離開實驗室
I thought it meant something else.
我以為它有別的意思
Yeah, well, I really actually wanted to say...
對，事實上，我想說…
that.
那個
But I figured I probably shouldn't because...
我想或許我不該說，因為…
I have to leave.
我得離開
No, you're right. Don't say it.
不，你說的對，別說
I do, though.
但我真的那麼想
I do too.
我也是
Well, bye, Phoebe.
再見，菲比
Now's not the time, Joey. You can yell at me tomorrow.
現在不是時候 喬伊，明天你可以罵我
Wait, no, Phoebe. I'm not gonna yell at you.
等一下，不，菲比 我不會罵你
I just started thinking about you and David...
我只是開始想到你跟大衛…
and I remember how bummed you were the first time he left.
我記得他第一次離開時你有多難過
Oh, Phoebe, come here.
菲比，過來
-Are you okay? -No, I'm not okay.
-你還好吧？ -不，我一點都不好
The only guy I've ever been crazy about is going to Minsk...
我唯一喜歡的男人要去明斯克…
and I may never see him again.
或許我永遠都不會再見到他
You could always visit him.
你可以去看他
Right. Like they'll let me have a passport.
對，你以為他們會給我護照
Anything I can do? Whatever you need.
有什麼我可以幫忙的嗎？什麼都行
Well, now...
喔…
if you achieve distillation of subatomic particles before he does...
如果你可以比他先 蒸餾出副原子粒子…
then he could come back.
他就可以回來了
I could give it a shot.
我可以試試看
Oh, look! There's a piece that doesn't have floor on it.
你看！有一小塊沒有沾到地板
-Stick to your side! -Come on, now!
-別越界！ -快點！
All right, what are we having?
好了，我們要吃什麼？
Oh, wait, I forgot my wrap.
等一下，我忘了拿披肩
Okay, wait here.
好吧，你在這裡等我
Hi, sweetie! Are you leaving?
嗨，甜心！你要走了嗎？
-Well.. -Give us a kiss. Come on.
-喔… -親阿姨一下，快點
Why? Why on the lips?
為什麼？為什麼要親嘴巴？